A Guide to the Richmond, Fredericksburg, and Potomac Railroad Records, 1834-1997
Library of Virginia
- Series III: Finance Department, 1834-1995, 68.2 cubic feet and 371 volumes. (Box 64-255)
  - III.D. Tax Records 1914-1992
    - III.D.2. State Tax Reports, Tax Returns, and Rolling Stock Information, 1933-1991
      - III.D.2.3. State Tax Return Rolling Stock Information (Class 5 Schedules)
        - Rolling Stock Information 1943 (Box-folder 243:4)
        - Rolling Stock Information 1944 (Box-folder 243:5)
        - Rolling Stock Information 1945 (Box-folder 243:6)
        - Rolling Stock Information 1946-1948 (Box-folder 244:1)
        - Rolling Stock Information 1949-1950 (Box-folder 244:2)
        - Rolling Stock Information 1951-1952 (Box-folder 244:3)
        - Rolling Stock Information 1953-1955 (Box-folder 244:4)
        - Rolling Stock Information 1956-1957 (Box-folder 244:5)
        - Rolling Stock Information 1958-`959 (Box-folder 245:1)
        - Rolling Stock Information 1960-1961 (Box-folder 245:2)
    - III.D.3. Property/Real Estate Tax ca. 1980-1992
      Divided into two sections according to internally existing filing units
      - III.D.3.1. Assessments
        - Tax year 1954; Assessment (Box-folder 246:1)
        - Tax year 1980-1992; Leases and sales information from Real Estate (Box-folder 246:2-3)
        - Tax year 1988; Correspondence and Forms (Box-folder 246:4)
        - Tax year 1988; Reassessment notices (Box-folder 246:5-7)
        - Tax year 1988; Tax receipts (Box-folder 246:8-10)
        - Tax year 1989; Corrected assessments, final and supplemental tax bills (Box-folder 246:11-12)
        - Tax year 1989; Land transactions, 3 folders (Box-folder 247:1-3)
        - Tax year 1989; Reassessment notices, 3 folders (Box-folder 247:4-6)
        - Tax year 1990; Assessment questions Fairfax County (Box-folder 247:7)
        - Tax year 1991; Localities C-H, 2 folders (Box-folder 247:8-9)
        - Tax year 1991-1992; Arlington County and Alexandria gross receipts (Box-folder 247:10)
        - Tax year 1992; Real Estate Forecast (22 Jan 1992), presented to Richmond Real Estate Group (Box-folder 247:11)
      - III.D.3.2. "Property taxes - current folders" 1988-1992
        Internal filing numbers in [ ]; an index precedes the files, but not all files listed in the index can be found in this collection.
        - Tax case - index 1991-1992 (Box-folder 248:1)
        - [1] Assessment, including Arlington-Alexandria reassessment 1991 (Box-folder 248:2)
        - [3] Assessment, ATF 1988 (Box-folder 248:3)
        - Assessment, ATF 1989 (Box-folder 248:4)
        - [10] Assessment, General 1990 (Box-folder 248:5)
        - [11] ATF Review 1990 (Box-folder 248:6)
        - [18] Assessment, Hanover Co./Ashland 1990 (Box-folder 248:7)
        - [20] DOT Reinvestment 1991, Charlies Young - Unit Value (Box-folder 248:8-10)
        - [33] Tax estimates (after transaction) Mar 1992 (Box-folder 248:11)
        - [34] Tax case estimate (tax liability model) No. 4 Apr 1992 (Box-folder 248:12)
        - [40] Tax case, Appeal to [W.H.] Forst [Tax Commissioner] 1988-1992 (Box-folder 248:13-14)
        - [41] Tax case, Appeal to [W.H.] Forst [Tax Commissioner], Misc. Correspondence 1991 (Box-folder 248:15)
        - [50] Current Activity 1987-1991 (Box-folder 248:16)
        - [90] Assessment Review Procedure - Pending, Appeal Deadlines 1990 (Box-folder 248:17)
        - [110] Paid Reciepts 1991 (Box-folder 248:18)
        - [120] Real Estate Taxes Paid; Summary per CAW 1990-1991 (Box-folder 248:19)
    - III.D.4. Miscellaneous Tax Subject files 1914-1973
      Files cover federal, municipal, as well as state taxes
      - Amortization 1941-1951 (Box-folder 249:1-6)
      - Excess profit tax; Excess profit data 1941-1942 (Box-folder 250:1-2)
        [73-14] Includes tax forms, correspondence, tax bulletins and reports, and research insititute publications
      - Excess profit tax; Excess profit taxes relief 1941-1942 (Box-folder 250:3-4)
        [73-14A; section 722] Includes tax forms, correspondence, tax reports, and income statistics
      - Federal Income Tax: Tax calculations and letters 1941-1949 (Box-folder 250:5)
      - Federal tax on transportation of persons and freight: Correspondence and regulations 1941-1957 (Box-folder 250:1-2)
      - Federal Tax on transportation of persons and freight: Exemption from Federal Transportation Tax 1941-1943 (Box-folder 251:1-2)
      - Federal tax on transportation of persons and freight: Profit and loss and other analysis (735A; section 734) 1917-1952 (Box-folder 251:3-5)
      - Federal tax on transportation of persons and freight: Returns (form 720), payment voucher, and receipts 1951-1959 (Box-folder 251:6-8)
      - Internal Revenue Service, Report of Examination for 1954-1964 (Box-folder 252:1-8)
      - Municipal taxes: Sewer taxes 1938-1952 (Box-folder 252:9)
      - State Corporation Commission Committee: Formula Study No. 1 1950-1953 (Box-folder 253:1-3)
      - State Corporation Commission Committee: Formula Study No. 2 1942-1953 (Box-folder 253:4-5)
      - State Tax Conference, R.R. of Virginia, Assessment 1922-1923 (Box-folder 253:6)
      - State Tax Conference, R.R. of Virginia, Meetings 1925-1930 (Box-folder 253:7-9)
      - State Tax Conference, R.R. of Virginia, "Out of date" 1914-1928 (Box-folder 253:10-12)
        Includes correspondence, bills, calculations, and schedules
      - State Taxes: General information on Virginia State Taxes 1917-1941 (Box-folder 254:1-7)
      - Tax case: R.F. & P. Railroad Co. v. R.F. & P. and Richmond & Petersburg Connection Co., 1925 (Box-folder 255:1-3)
        includes correspondence, stipulation, and supporting financial data, 1917-1926
      - Taxes on Dividends (Stockholders) for the Tax years 1913-1921 (Box-folder 255:4)
- Series IV: Transportation Department, n.d., 1858-1929, .225 cubic feet and two volumes. (Box 256-258)
  The records of the General Superintendent's office, E.T.D. Myers at the time, who would be the R.F.& P. President from 1889 to 1905, consist of one letter book, recording outgoing correspondence from 4 May 1882-20 Nov. 1882.
  There are a few more miscellaneous items in this series: three broadsides, one depicting directions for the operation of the heating systems of the private car Berwick, n.d.; one Resolution in Regard to Free Travel, 1858; and a reward poster relating to the 1894 Mail Train Robbery near Aquia Creek. Of note is also a transportation order furnished by the Office of the Chief Quartermaster of the Army of the James, dated June 10, 1865. Also included are a baggage tag, ticket stubs, and one volume, 1912-1929, with alphabetized entries of religious groups, educational and non-profit organizations, listing individual members of each group; possibly to record free or discounted travel.
  - IV.A. General Superintendent's Office: Correspondence, 1882, 1 vol. (original and copy); original volume VERY fragile: spine missing, some pages damaged, others torn out; hard to read or missing letters, words, and passages. Photocopy provides same level of legibility as the original. (Box 256-257)
  - IV.B. Miscellaneous Records, n.d., 1858-1929
    Arranged chronologically.
    - Private Car "Berwick," Directions for Operating Heating Systems (Vapor Car Heating Co., Inc.) (Broadside), n.d., Oversize. (Box-folder 344:38)
    - Baggage Tag, Baltimore & Richmond, via B. & O. and R.F. & P., No. 124 (brass) (Box-folder 258:1)
    - Resolution in Regard to Free Travel (Broadside), 21 Jun 1858 (Box-folder 258:2)
    - Ticket stubs, various lines, all issued by R.F. & P.R.R., n.d., Jan-Feb 1868 (Box-folder 258:3)
    - Transportation order furnished by the Office of the Chief Quartermaster, Army of the James, 10 Jun 1865 (Box-folder 258:4)
    - Reward Poster relating to Mail Train Robbery near Aquia Creek (Broadside), 12 Oct 1894, Oversize. (Box-folder 344:38)
      Reads: $1000 Reward! Will Be Paid By The Richmond, Fredericksburg and Potomac Railroad Company
    - Alphabetized Entries, 1912-1929, 1 vol. (Box 258)
      Includes: religious groups, educational and non-profit organizations, listing individual members of each group; possibly to record free or discounted travel. Some names have notation "trip," most others "none;" as well as dates.
- Series V: Maintenance of Way Department, Engineering, Technology, Research, etc., n.d., 1889-1986, 1.35 cubic feet and 4 volumes. (Box 258-261)
  This series is divided into three subseries: A. Engineering; B. Research; and C. New Technologies. Of note are one volume of drawings and specifications of sections for bridge construction, 1903-1907, and two record books, 1889-1890, for the construction of the James River Branch. Those volumes also include data for the James River Bridge. The collection also comprises plans and drawings for about 500 architectural and engineering projects, which will have been separated from the main body of the collection and which will be described separately by the Library of Virginia's architectural records archivist. See also Series IX: Photographs.
  - V.A. Engineering, 1889-1946
    - Culverts and Bridges, Acca to Penola, Apr 1903-Mar 1907, 1 vol. (Box 258)
      Drawings, mostly sections, in ink, and brief specifications.
    - General Specifications for Concrete Work, n.d., Typescript copy. (Box-folder 258:5)
    - James River Branch R.R.: Record book No. 1, Harman & Co., 1889-1890, 1 vol. (Box 258)
      Includes James River Bridge data.
    - James River Branch R.R.: Record book No. 2, Mason, Hoge & Co., 1890, 1 vol. (Box 258)
    - Pile Driving: Field Record of Pile Driving (No. 5), Nov 1945-Jun 1946 (Box-folder 259:1-9)
    - Pile Driving Record and Summary Pile Driving Record at Aquia Creek Bd., Jun 1945-Aug 1946 (Box-folder 260:1-8)
  - V.B. Research, 1965-1972, Scrapbook (clippings, photographs, invitations, announcements), 6 folders.
    - VISR (Virginia Insitute for Scientific Research) History, 1965-1970 [i.e., 1964-1972] (Box-folder 261:1-6)
  - V.C. New Technologies, 1986, 1 vol.
    - MCI Telecommunications Corporation, Lightwave Systems: Plans for Project 03124, 1986, 1994 (Volume on shelf)
- Series VI: Public Relations Department, Advertising and Marketing, n.d., 1945, 1984, 1997
  - Overnight Service Richmond-Washington-Baltimore Brochure, n.d. (Box-folder 261:7)
  - Train image and line logo (stamped), n.d., 2 items. (Box-folder 261:8)
  - Richmond, Fredericksburg and Potomac Railroad in World War II, Sep 1945, 1 leaf. (Box-folder 261:9)
  - VRS (Caroline Fleming), Richmond, to LF Strategic Realty Investor, NY, 1997, One letter with attachments. (Box-folder 261:10)
  - R.F. & P.R. Company: One Hundred and Fiftieth Anniversary, (25 Feb 1834-25 Feb 1984) 1984, Oversize; 5 copies; broadside, 19 x 25 inches. (Box-folder 344:39)
- Series VII: Membership in Societies and Associations, etc., 1923
  - Old Colony Club, Permanent Membership certificate for Stuart C. Leake, 11 June 1923 (Box-folder 261:11)
- Series VIII: Publications Department, 1934-1991, .675 cubic feet and 2 volumes. (Box 262-264)
  Includes subseries A. Corporate History; and B. Newsletters
  - VIII.A. Corporate History, 1940, ca. 1963
    One of the histories was compiled by an R.F.& P. traffic manager, John B. Mordecai, A Brief History of the Richmond, Fredericksburg & Potomac Railroad, 1940. The 98 page volume reproduces images; the other history is a manuscript, ca. 1963 by Garnett Laidlaw Eskew: Bridge Line, The Life and Times of the Richmond, Fredericksburg & Potomac Railroad, 1834-1963.
    - Garnett Laidlaw Eskew: Bridge Line, ... Introduction (Box-folder 262:1)
    - Garnett Laidlaw Eskew: Bridge Line, ... Chapter 1 (Box-folder 262:2)
    - Garnett Laidlaw Eskew: Bridge Line, ... Chapter 2 (Box-folder 262:3)
    - Garnett Laidlaw Eskew: Bridge Line, ... Chapter 3 (Box-folder 262:4)
    - Garnett Laidlaw Eskew: Bridge Line, ... Chapter 4 (Box-folder 262:5)
    - Garnett Laidlaw Eskew: Bridge Line, ... Chapter 5 (Box-folder 262:6)
    - Garnett Laidlaw Eskew: Bridge Line, ... Chapter 6 (Box-folder 262:7)
    - Garnett Laidlaw Eskew: Bridge Line, ... Chapter 7 (Box-folder 262:8)
    - Garnett Laidlaw Eskew: Bridge Line, ... Chapter 8 (Box-folder 262:9)
    - Garnett Laidlaw Eskew: Bridge Line, ... Chapter 9 (Box-folder 262:10)
    - Garnett Laidlaw Eskew: Bridge Line, ... Chapter 10 (Box-folder 262:11)
    - Garnett Laidlaw Eskew: Bridge Line, ... Chapter 11 (Box-folder 262:12)
    - Garnett Laidlaw Eskew: Bridge Line, ... Chapter 12 (Box-folder 262:13)
    - Garnett Laidlaw Eskew: Bridge Line, ... Chapter 13 (Box-folder 262:14)
    - Garnett Laidlaw Eskew: Bridge Line, ... Chapter 14 (Box-folder 262:15)
    - Garnett Laidlaw Eskew: Bridge Line, ... Chapter 15 (Box-folder 262:16)
    - Garnett Laidlaw Eskew: Bridge Line, ... Chapters 16-29 (Box-folder 262:17)
    - Garnett Laidlaw Eskew: Bridge Line, ... Chapters 19A-22 (Box-folder 263:1)
    - Garnett Laidlaw Eskew: Bridge Line, ... Chapters 23-25 (Box-folder 263:2)
    - Garnett Laidlaw Eskew: Bridge Line, ... Chapters 26-29 (Box-folder 263:3)
    - John B. Mordecai: A Brief History of the Richmond, Fredericksburg & Potomac Railroad, 1940 and 1941 (reprint), 1 vol. (2 copies)
  - VIII.B. Newsletters, 1934-1935, 1984-1991
    - R.F. & P. Bulletin, Newsletter, Dec 1934-May 1935, Volume III, No. 1-3 (Box-folder 264:1)
    - Data Link Newsletter (3 to 4 issues per calendar year) Vol. 1, No. 1-4, 1984 (Box-folder 264:2)
    - Data Link Newsletter (3 to 4 issues per calendar year) Vol. 2, No. 1-4, 1985 (Box-folder 264:3)
    - Data Link Newsletter (3 to 4 issues per calendar year) Vol. 3, No. 1-4, 1986 (Box-folder 264:4)
    - Data Link Newsletter (3 to 4 issues per calendar year) Vol. 4, No. 1-4, 1987 (Box-folder 264:5)
    - Data Link Newsletter (3 to 4 issues per calendar year) Vol. 5, No. 2-4, 1988 (Box-folder 264:6)
    - Data Link Newsletter (3 to 4 issues per calendar year) Vol. 6, No. 1-4, 1989 (Box-folder 264:7)
    - Data Link Newsletter (3 to 4 issues per calendar year) Vol. 7, No. 1-3 and Vol. 8, No. 1, 1990, 1991 (Box-folder 264:8)
- Series IX: Photographs, 1920-1990, n.d. (Volume on shelf)
  Originals are in Boxes 265-267, and oversize in Box 344, folder 38.
  Patrons are to use copies in photograph binder instead of original photographs.
  - Group 1: Broad Street Station Pictures (Photographs of Union Station on West Broad St., Richmond, Va., a.k.a. Broad St. Station (Volume on shelf (barcode 0005623726))
    There are 58 Broad Street Station photographs, dating from about 1919 to the 1960's. Many photographs are undated, but most dates can be narrowed down by comparison with dated images, and by evidence such as the styles of cars and clothing. Images include exterior and aerial views from different angles, as well as waiting rooms, dining rooms, a Christmas scene, and a ticket counter.
    Originals in Box 265.
    Photographs numbered 1-58.
    Access Restriction:
    Use copies in photograph binder (barcode 0005623726) instead of originals.
    - 1. [Aerial View] Easterly across town, Richmond, Va., Broad St. Station at left, n.d., 8 x 10 (11029;021) Underwood & Underwood, Aerial Dept., N.Y.
    - 2. [Side view on columns and front entrance doors], n.d., 8 x 10
    - 3. [Front and Side View with cars in parking lot], [192- ], 8 x 10; stamped: Foster, Richmond, Va.
    - 4. [Christmas tree], n.d., 8 x 10
    - 5. [Front view, with construction], n.d., 8 x 10; (1;A)
    - 6. Christmas Tree Broad St. Station [with model train] (1), 1934, 8 x 10
    - 7. Christmas Tree Broad St. Station [with model train] (2), 1934, 8 x 10
    - 8. [Front view with parked cars], [194- ], 8 x 10
    - 9. John Russell Pope: Broad Street Station, Richmond, 1913-1919, ca. 1919, 8 x 10
    - 10. Broad Street Station [Front view], 17 Mar 1962, 8 x 10; C; "Broad Street Station" written in black marker on front
    - 11. [Front view, showing street car tracks on Broad St.], n.d., 8 x 10
    - 12. Broad Street Station [Front view], Nov 1963, 8 x 10
    - 13. [Front and side with parked cars], [1940-195- ], 8 x 10; 76 K; photograph by Wray Selden, Photographer, Richmond, Va.
    - 14. [Front view with parked cars], [1940-195- ], 8 x 10; 76 K; photograph by Wray Selder, photographer, Richmond, Va.
    - 15. Broad Street Station [Front view], December 1963, 8 x 10
    - 16. Broad Street Station [Front view], November 1962, 8 x 10; 2 copies
    - 17. [Front view with parked cars], [1960-197- ], 8 x 10; 2 copies
    - 18. [Front view with trees and parking meters], [1960-197- ], 8 x 10
    - 19. [Front and side view with parked cars], [1960-197- ], 8 x 10
    - 20. [Front and side view with parked cars], [194- ], 8 x 10; Dementi Studio, Grace at Second, Richmond 19, Ca.
    - 21. [Front view with trees, showing street car tracks], [192- ], 8 x 10
    - 22. [Front view with parked cars], [1960-197- ], 8 x 10
    - 23. [Partial front view], [1960-197- ], 8 x 10
    - 24. Broad Street Station [Front view with snow], Jan 1964, 8 x 10
    - 25. [main waiting room with people assembled for special occasion/celebration], [1930-194- ], 8 x 10; F
    - 26. [Front view], [197- ], 8 x 10
    - 27. [Aerial view, showing Broad Street and tracks behind station], [192- ], 8 x 10
    - 28. [Front view with parking lot and traffic light], [196- ], 8 x 10; Arthur Clarke Studio, Richmond, Va.
    - 29. Broad Street Station [Side view showing tracks], Nov 1962, 8 x 10
    - 30. Broad Street Station [Side view showing tracks - close-up], Nov 1962, 8 x 10
    - 31. [Main waiting room, construction], [ca. 1919?], 8 x 10
    - 32. [Christmas tree with model train and model of Broad Street Station], n.d., 8 x 10; 2 copies
    - 33. [Main waiting room], n.d., 8 x 10
    - 34. Broad Street Station, Colored Waiting Room, Richmond, Va., [ca. 1919], 8 x 10
    - 35. Floor Plan, Broad St. Station, Richmond, Va [John Russell Pope, Architect], [1917], 8 x 10; 2 copies
    - 36. [Dining room (1)], n.d., 8 x 10; imprinted in corner "Cook"
    - 37. [Dining room (2)], n.d., 8 x 10
    - 38. J-15-Penna [i.e., Union, a.k.a. Broad St.] Station, Richmond, Va., from Airship J.O.U.S. 1; by Photo School L.F., 9 Mar 1920, 8 x 10; mounted on cardboard; damaged, take to lab
    - 39. [Front view, showing Broad St. and street car tracks]; shows some construction, [1919-192- ], 8 x 10
    - 40. Dining room and bar, n.d., 8 x 10; imprinted in corner "Cook"
    - 41. [Christmas tree with model train and model of Broad St. Station], n.d., 8 x 10
    - 42. [Front view, showing Broad Street and street car tracks]; includes letter from James L. Owens to Mr. Elliott, 10 Mar 1924, Jan 1919, 8 x 10; clipping on back of photograph regarding cost of station
    - 43. [Aerial view], n.d., 8 x 10
    - 44. [Partial view of back side, showing tracks and platforms], 8 x 10
    - 45. [Aerial view], n.d., 8 x 10; (13243-11); T.V. & Motion Picture Productions, Inc., Richmond 19, Va.
    - 46. [aerial view] compare to #45; same view from greater distance, n.d., 8 x 10; [T.V. & Motion Picture Productions, Inc., Richmond 19, Va.?]
    - 47. [Aerial view], n.d., 8 x 10
    - 48. [Aerial Front view, showing area behind the station], [192- ], 8 x 10; Dementi Studio, Richmond VA
    - 49. [Lunch room], n.d., 8 x 10
    - 50. Broad St. Station, Richmond, Va. [aerial view, showing tracks behind station], [192- ], 8 x 10; 7 copies
    - 51. [Aerial Front view, showing tracks behind the station]; includes negative, [192- ], 8 x 10; Dementi Studio, Richmond, VA; 2 copies
    - 52. [Front view, construction], [ca. 1919], 8 x 10; 2 copies
    - 53. [Aerial view], n.d., 8 x 10
    - 54. Broad Street Station [main waiting room], Nov 1962, 8 x 10
    - 55. [Ticket counter] marked up for publication, [ca. 1957], 8 x 10
    - 56. Broad St. Station [aerial view], n.d., 8 x 10; #30
    - 57. [Back view, showing tracks and AMTRAK train leaving station], n.d., 8 x 10 color
    - 58. [Front view, close-up, with storage trucks], n.d., 8 x 10
  - Group 2: Steam Locomotive Pictures (Volume on shelf (barcode 0005623726))
    The 36 images in the Steam Locomotive group also comprise rail yard pictures, and several passenger cars, as well as the Cannonball Wreck at Dunlop Station, 1903. The steam engines depicted are from a line of engines acquired in the late 1930's and early 1940's. The freight train engines were named after Confederate generals, the passenger train engines after governors. Most engines depicted date from the 1920's through 1940's.
    Photographs numbered 59-94.
    - 59. General Robert E. Lee: Engineer's Side of Back Head Showing Reverse Lever, Throttle, Train Control, Air Gauges, etc. (Locos. 551-555 Class), Apr 1937, 8 x 10; a; Picture No. 29; 11357-1 right, 16-482/4 E105-09; see also #78
    - 60. Engine number 574(?), n.d., 8 x 10; R471 on face of photograph
    - 61. [General Robert E. Lee; close-up of side-window]; women leaning out of the window, n.d., 8 x 10; Dementi Studio, Richmond, VA
    - 62. [Women with oil can posing next to driving gear], n.d., 8 x 10; Dementi Studio, Richmond, VA
    - 63. Locomotive Class 551-555 [driving gear close-up], n.d., 8 x 10; 11359
    - 64. [Interior view of cab of an engine], n.d., 8 x 10
    - 65. General Robert E. Lee: View of Back Head of Locomotive From Tender - Locomotives Class 551-555 (copy 1); Locomotives Class 551-555, Interior View of Cab of Engine Photographed From Ground Level (copy 2), n.d., 8 x 10; 11359-2; #30 (two identical copies each with different title on back)
    - 66. Tender, General Robert E. Lee, #551 (copy 1); General Robert E. Lee: View of Front of Tender From Locomotive Cab; Locomotives Class 551-555, 8 x 10; 11358; two identical copies each with different title on back; #28
    - 67. [Rectangular tender: Capital Cities Route, Richmond-Washington], 12 Feb 1943, 8 x 10; 1168-3; Lima Locomotive Works, Inc.; 2 copies
    - 68. R.F. & P. Passenger Train pulled by one of the "Governors", Between Pot[omac] Yard and Alexa[ndria] Pass[enger] Sta[tion], 8 x 10; marked up
    - 69. [Engine No. 38] Built in 1902 by the Richmond Locomotive Works, n.d., 8 x 10
    - 70. [Engine class 555 pulling freight train], n.d., 8 x 10; copy 1: 14694;B; marked up; copy 2 is a close-up without marking or notes on the back
    - 71. The Cannon Ball Wreck At Dunlop Station, 26 Jun 1903, 8 x 10; 2 copies
    - 72. Drop Pit in Round House, 21 Jan 1924, 8 x 10
    - 73. [Engine No. 8], n.d., 8 x 10
    - 74. [Engine No. 325, Capital Cities Route, Richmond and Washington], n.d., 7.5 x 3; 9900; 540
    - 75. [Engine No. 2, Richmond-Washington Line], 7.5 x 3; 5601; 543
    - 76. [Engine pulling freight train], n.d., 7 x 5; 5143-39(2)
    - 77. [Engine 552, General T.J. Jackson, with tender, Capital Cities Route, Richmond-Washington], n.d., 8 x 10
    - 78. [General Robert E. Lee, left side of back head, showing mechanical details] Locos. 551-555 class, Apr 1937, 8 x 10; 11357 Left, 16-482/4; E105-09; (see also #59)
    - 79. [Engine 402 with tender], n.d., 8 x 10
    - 80. [Engine] class 4-6-2 No. 301, Ivy City Engine, Terminal, Washington, D.C., n.d., 8 x 10; 5
    - 81. [Rail yard scene], 8 x 10; 2848
    - 82. [Rail yard with freight trains], n.d., 8 x 10; C-2806
    - 83. Governor Class 4-8-4 No. 602, Acca Engine Terminal late 1940's, 8 x 10
    - 84. Silver Star - Train No. 21, Rappahannock River Bridge, [Class] 484, No. 621, late 1940's, 8 x 10
    - 85. [Aerial view of derailed passenger train in rail yard], n.d., 8 x 10; 3
    - 86. [Freight train leaving Potomac Yard, Washington Monument in background], n.d., 8 x 10; 11306
    - 87. [Two Richmond-Washington Line passenger cars], n.d., 8 x 10; 22638 & 640; 11208
    - 88. [Richmond-Washington Line passenger car], n.d., 7 x 9; 8 x 10; 3 copies
    - 89. [Acca Yard] Oiling Station [e.g., Coaling Station] and Oil House [e.g., Round House], 21 Jan 1924, 8 x 10